DANIEL SMITHER

https://smitherd9.github.io

Home: 804 997 9930 - smitherd9@gmail.com

Summary

Web developer and designer specializing in front end development who enjoys building applications and websites.

Skills

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript

jQuery

MERN stack of MongoDB, Express, React and NodeJS

Twitter Bootstrap

Unit testing using Mocha and Chai

ES6 syntax

Web Projects

Old News https://smitherd9.github.io/old_news/

A web application allowing users to search The New York Times and The Guardian for news articles and stories in the recent past.

HTML 5 Javascript / jQuery **Twitter Bootstrap** CSS 3 NY Times Article Search API The Guardian API

What Are The Chances?

https://boiling-shelf-21235.herokuapp.com/

A web application allowing users to guery the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene in New York City for restaurant inspection data.

 HTML 5 Javascript / jQuery **Express** Chai Nock CSS 3 Node.js Unirest Mocha Travis CI

What Are The Chances?

https://calm-sands-83203.herokuapp.com/

-- Death in NYC

A web application using NYC's Open Data API to get data on leading causes of death in the city for the years 2007 to 2014.

HTML 5 Javascript React/Redux React Bootstrap Node.js Chai CSS 3 C3.js React Router Travis CI **Express** Mocha

Education and Training

Virginia Commonwealth University, 2019

B.A. Music with minor in Religious Studies — Richmond, VA, United States

Studied and performed double bass under the instruction of Victor Dvoskin and Kelly Ali in Richmond, Virginia from 2006 - 2010

Thinkful, 2017

Flexible Web Development Bootcamp — Online, United States

Studied core web development technologies and built web apps utilizing both front end and back end tech under the mentorship of Vincent Ramdhanie

Institut Seni Indonesia, 2013

Music — Denpasar, Bali, Indonesia

Darmasiswa Scholarship Program in Balinese Gamelan Music

Studied and performed Balinese Gamelan Gong Kebyar and Gamelan Gender Wayang with master musicians while living in Bali, Indonesia from 2012 - 2015

Experience

Web Assistant

February 2019 to current

Virginia Commonwealth University School of Medicine - https://medschool.vcu.edu/

Assist in migrating content to the new School of Medicine website and build web pages for various departments

Remote Web Developer Intern

September 2018 to May 2019

Pay Your Tuition Funds - https://www.gopyt.com/

Built backend to capture offers from banks looking to fund students, modified web pages and implemented new designs

Remote Web Developer Intern

October 2017 to May 2018

LivestockCity - https://www.livestockcity.com/

Assisted with frontend development and debugging to ensure a seamless experience across various devices

Online English Teacher

September 2013 to Current

English Online Study (eostudy.com), Online English Boston Club (oe-boston.com) — Remote Teaching English to students online from all over the world including China, Saudi Arabia, Japan and South Korea

Copywriter

March 2012 to March 2013

Private Leisure International — Denpasar, Bali

Write descriptions of villa properties in Bali and elsewhere in Southeast Asia.